<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Krystina Shveda&#39;s Stories</title>
    <description>This is a blog written by Krystina Shveda about journalism, life and tea.
</description>
    <link>http://krystinashveda.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://krystinashveda.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 19:27:02 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 19:27:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kurdish delegation demands UK&#39;s support in fighting ISIS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the Syrian city of Kobane keeps resisting the Islamic State’s attacks, a delegation of Kurdish protesters is meeting MPs across London demanding proper help from the British government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/80627489/krystinashveda.com/Kurdish%20protests/333.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeremy Corbyn MP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jeremy-corbyn-the-mp-for-north-islington-to-lobby-helping-kurdish-kobane&quot;&gt;Jeremy Corbyn, the MP for North Islington, to lobby helping Kurdish Kobane&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;a href=&quot;http://uk.reuters.com/article/2014/09/26/us-syria-crisis-coalition-factbox-idUSKCN0HL2DL20140926&quot;&gt;the UK has joined International Coalition Against Islamic State&lt;/a&gt; and agreed to conduct air strikes over Iraq, the Parliament is reluctant to allow military operations over the territory of Syria, ruled by a hostile President Bashar al-Assad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Corbyn, who voted against joining anti-ISIS coalition before its strikes focused on Kobane, committed himself to lobbying support to the Kurdish city at the Parliament during his speech to Kurdish protesters at the Parliament Square on October 14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hope MP&amp;#39;s think before Parliamentary vote: Bombing will make the Isis problem worse | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/guardianletters&quot;&gt;@guardianletters&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#10; &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/KxvbGgp46a&quot;&gt;http://t.co/KxvbGgp46a&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/guardian&quot;&gt;@guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jeremy Corbyn MP (@jeremycorbyn) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeremycorbyn/status/514703922968027137&quot;&gt;September 24, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delegates demanded conducting air strikes against ISIS over Kobane, providing armoury to YPG (People’s Protection Units) guerilla fighters who defend the city and convincing Turkey to help Kobane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“ISIS is growing. Today it’s Kurdistan, tomorrow it can be London,” one of the protesters said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/80627489/krystinashveda.com/Kurdish%20protests/222.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kurdish protesters at Parliament Square&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Kurdish protesters at Parliament Square on October 14. At the front are Kurdistan flag and the flag of Kurdish guerilla fighters (YPG)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;demand-to-convince-turkey-in-helping-kurds&quot;&gt;Demand to convince Turkey in helping Kurds&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The protesters chanted “Wake up, UK! Wake up, UK! Turkey is for ISIS!”, asking the UK authorities to influence Turkey &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/oct/14/turkey-inaction-kobani-kurdish-peace-politics&quot;&gt;whose silence they regard as the support for ISIS&lt;/a&gt;. Kurdish population has been a sensitive issue for Turkey for decades, since the Kurds used to demand independence. Kurdistan Workers’ Party (PKK) is considered a terrorist body by Turkey, US and EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/109684832&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/109684832&quot;&gt;Kurdish protesters&#39; chants&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user14398107&quot;&gt;Krystsina Shveda&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am here especially for Kobane. Civilian people are like in a prison there, being attacked by ISIS from 3 sides and by Turkey on the other side. Women die, children have no food. Please, help us,” another protester begged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;jeremy-corbyn-mp-to-push-demands-on-turkey&quot;&gt;Jeremy Corbyn MP to push demands on Turkey&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his speech to protesters, Corbyn said that he would try to manipulate in the Parliament that the threat to Kurdish people comes not only to from ISIS forces but also, even more importantly, from the Turkish government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Since Turkey is a member of NATO and our very close ally, we expect the British government to be making demands on the Turkish government about humanitarian aid, safe corridors, the movement of refugees, practical support of the Kurdish people,” he stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/80627489/krystinashveda.com/Kurdish%20protests/444.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeremy Corbyn MP speeks to protesters&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jeremy Corbyn MP speaks to protesters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 29-year-old Islington Councillor Aysegul Erdogan spoke to Corbyn on the side of the Kurdish delegation. “We know that Jeremy Corbyn was one of the MPs who said no to airstrikes in Iraq. But his approach to Kobane and our demands was different this time,” she said. According to Erdogan, MP Corbyn agreed to get answers from the Foreign and Commonwealth Office on how the UK could help defeating ISIS in Kobane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our heart lies with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Kobane?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Kobane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Aysegul Erdogan (@aysemeleti) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aysemeleti/status/522176567880208384&quot;&gt;October 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corbyn’s speech, followed by a massive applause, finished with the words of encouragement stating that the common goal of political settlement in the whole Middle East region “must include the right of all the Kurdish people to self-determination regarding their own future, within or without existing national boarders.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The position of the UK government on this issue remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: on Tuesday, October 21, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/middle-east/uk-drones-ready-to-attack-isis-in-syriaand-iraq-9807281.html&quot;&gt;British aircraft has been readied for flights over Kobane to fight Isis in Syria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 16:50:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://krystinashveda.com/Kurdish-delegation-against-ISIS</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krystinashveda.com/Kurdish-delegation-against-ISIS</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kurdish protesters demand UK support in fight against ISIS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the Syrian city of Kobane retains its 34th day of Islamic State resistance backed by US’s weapon airdrops and air strikes, Kurdish population in the UK continues to march with protests in London, demanding proper help from the British government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/80627489/krystinashveda.com/Kurdish%20protests/222.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kurdish protesters at Parliament Square&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Kurdish protesters at Parliament Square on October 14. At the front are Kurdistan flag and the the flag of YPG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the UK has joined International Coalition Against Islamic State and agreed to conduct air strikes over Iraq who have requested international help, the Parliament is reluctant to allow military operations over the territory of Syria ruled by a hostile President Bashar al-Assad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The protesters chant “Wake up UK, wake up UK, terrorists are ISIS”, asking the UK government to influence Turkey whose silence they regard as support for ISIS. Kurds living in Turkey also protested, which led to severe clashes with the police. Kurdish population is a sensitive issue for Turkey because Turkey, US and EU consider Kurdish PKK a terrorist party. Thousands of refugees from Kobane are stuck at the Syrian-Turkish boarder with no way either back or forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/109684832&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/109684832&quot;&gt;Kurdish protesters&#39; chants&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user14398107&quot;&gt;Krystsina Shveda&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kurdish people also address civilian people in the UK in an attempt to raise their concern. “ISIS is growing and growing, today it is Kurdistan, tomorrow it can be London,” one of the protesters says. “Civilian people in Kobane are like in a prison, being attacked by ISIS from 3 sides and by Turkey on the other side. Women die, children have no food. So, I am here especially for Kobane, I only want everybody to hear our voice. Please, help us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A delegation of Kurds organised by the protesters arrange meetings with MPs across London to discuss the chances of convincing the Parliament to provide timely help. During one of the protest meeting at Parliament Square on October 14, the delegation talked to Jeremy Corbyn MP for North Islington who voted against joining anti-ISIS Coalition before ISIS strikes focused on Kobane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/80627489/krystinashveda.com/Kurdish%20protests/333.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeremy Corbyn MP&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jeremy Corbyn MP at the Kurdish protest in London&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hope MP&amp;#39;s think before Parliamentary vote: Bombing will make the Isis problem worse | &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/guardianletters&quot;&gt;@guardianletters&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#10; &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/KxvbGgp46a&quot;&gt;http://t.co/KxvbGgp46a&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/guardian&quot;&gt;@guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jeremy Corbyn MP (@jeremycorbyn) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeremycorbyn/status/514703922968027137&quot;&gt;September 24, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We know that Jeremy Corbyn was one of the MPs who said no to airstrikes in Iraq against the ISIS. But his approach to Kobane and his approach to our demands was a bit different this time,” a 29-year-old Islington Councillor and Kurdish delegate Aysegul Erdogan said. According to her, MP Corbyn agreed to take this question to the Foreign and Commonwealth Office and get answers to how the UK would intervene with defeating the ISIS in Kobane. The delegates asked to conduct airstrikes against ISIS over Kobane and to provide armoury to YPG (People’s Protection Units) guerilla fighters who defend the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our heart lies with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Kobane?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Kobane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Aysegul Erdogan (@aysemeleti) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aysemeleti/status/522176567880208384&quot;&gt;October 15, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his open speech to protesters, Jeremy Corbyn said that he was trying to manipulate in the Parliament that the threat to Kurdish people comes not only to from ISIS forces but also, even more importantly, from the Turkish government. “Since Turkey is a member of NATO and a very close ally of the British government, we expect the British government to be making some demands on the Turkish government about humanitarian aid, safe corridors, movement of refugees, practical support of the Kurdish people,” he stated.  Corbyn assumed that other MPs would join this position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A speech followed by a massive applause finished with the words of encouragement stating that the common goal of political settlement in the whole Middle East region “must include the right of all the Kurdish people to their self-determination, to decide their own future within or without existing national boarders”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/80627489/krystinashveda.com/Kurdish%20protests/444.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeremy Corbyn MP speeks to protesters&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jeremy Corbyn MP speeks to protesters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The position of the UK government on this issues remains unclear today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: on Tuesday, October 21, The Independent reported that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/middle-east/uk-drones-ready-to-attack-isis-in-syriaand-iraq-9807281.html&quot;&gt;British aircraft have been readied for flights over Syria in the war against Isis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 15:50:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://krystinashveda.com/Kurdish-protesters-against-ISIS</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krystinashveda.com/Kurdish-protesters-against-ISIS</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Journalism lab 1 at City</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-all-about-the-pace-of-learning&quot;&gt;It’s all about the pace of learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I knew something about Excel, but after our first data journalism workshop with John Burn-Murdoch, I think maybe not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a small compliment to John whom I happy to see as our teacher, but the whole drama around this for me is &lt;em&gt;the pace of learning&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered myself quite a fast learner. Throughout my 3+ years at a huge software services corporation, I had to be constantly learning new approaches and tools. There was no other choice if I wanted to adopt myself for more and more complex projects I pulled myself into. Not a big deal to spend &lt;em&gt;a couple weeks&lt;/em&gt; digging on the internet and learning by doing. The thing is that I was able to introduce innovation, whilst many others tended to stick to what they already knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I was lucky enough to have my own tiny room in the office and could invest time into experimenting. How come? This is Minsk, baby. The competition is not high enough to push you not only do cool things but also do them &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s compare a couple weeks and 2 hours in class - probably, for the same amount of knowledge. My mind was simply puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This compression of time is maybe the best thing about studying at City.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years passed after I first heard about data journalism (was immediately in love). By 2014, I’ve done &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; data visualisations. I’ve even been invited to talks on data journalism in Minsk. Because omg I was one of the avantguard characters in local journalism. But I still struggle to parrot a chain of operations in Excell at fast pace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, is it me or it is because I lived in a society that has a deceptive standard of success? Not like I stayed in a closed environment and couldn’t compare - I read industry news, attended international conferences. But there is no place like London that can show you so immediately what success means. It’s when you are chaging the world in two years after you’ve started learning. Because even two hours matter, it’s actually a massive amount of time to learn new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB Practical note: during the class, as a true geek, I tryed to document every step we took to be able to repeat the whole thing. Simply being able to follow the steps without remembering would be not good enough for me. This may be one of the reasons why I found it difficult to follow sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 12:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Talks and Meetups for Interhacktives - October agenda</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;12 free events an interactive journalist wants to attend in London:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?showTitle=0&amp;amp;showNav=0&amp;amp;showTz=0&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;wkst=2&amp;amp;bgcolor=%23FFFFFF&amp;amp;src=18e3kddq2kkqjloql39175pjeo%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;color=%23AB8B00&amp;amp;ctz=Europe%2FLondon&quot; style=&quot; border-width:0 &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 12:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
