<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Krystina Shveda&#39;s Stories</title>
    <description>This is a blog written by Krystina Shveda about journalism, life and tea.
</description>
    <link>http://krystinashveda.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://krystinashveda.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 19:51:18 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 19:51:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Journalism lab 1 at City</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-all-about-the-pace-of-learning&quot;&gt;It’s all about the pace of learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I knew something about Excel, but after our first data journalism workshop with John Burn-Murdoch, I think maybe not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a small compliment to John whom I happy to see as our teacher, but the whole drama around this for me is &lt;em&gt;the pace of learning&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered myself quite a fast learner. Throughout my 3+ years at a huge software services corporation, I had to be constantly learning new approaches and tools. There was no other choice if I wanted to adopt myself for more and more complex projects I pulled myself into. Not a big deal to spend &lt;em&gt;a couple weeks&lt;/em&gt; digging on the internet and learning by doing. The thing is that I was able to introduce innovation, whilst many others tended to stick to what they already knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I was lucky enough to have my own tiny room in the office and could invest time into experimenting. How come? This is Minsk, baby. The competition is not high enough to push you not only do cool things but also do them &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s compare a couple weeks and 2 hours in class - probably, for the same amount of knowledge. My mind was simply puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This compression of time is maybe the best thing about studying at City.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years passed after I first heard about data journalism (was immediately in love). By 2014, I’ve done &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; data visualisations. I’ve even been invited to talks on data journalism in Minsk. Because omg I was one of the avantguard characters in local journalism. But I still struggle to parrot a chain of operations in Excell at fast pace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, is it me or it is because I lived in a society that has a deceptive standard of success? Not like I stayed in a closed environment and couldn’t compare - I read industry news, attended international conferences. But there is no place like London that can show you so immediately what success means. It’s when you are chaging the world in two years after you’ve started learning. Because even two hours matter, it’s actually a massive amount of time to learn new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB Practical note: during the class, as a true geek, I tryed to document every step we took to be able to repeat the whole thing. Simply being able to follow the steps without remembering would be not good enough for me. This may be one of the reasons why I found it difficult to follow sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 12:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Talks and Meetups for Interhacktives - October agenda</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;12 free events an interactive journalist wants to attend in London:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?showTitle=0&amp;amp;showNav=0&amp;amp;showTz=0&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;wkst=2&amp;amp;bgcolor=%23FFFFFF&amp;amp;src=18e3kddq2kkqjloql39175pjeo%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;color=%23AB8B00&amp;amp;ctz=Europe%2FLondon&quot; style=&quot; border-width:0 &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 12:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://krystinashveda.com/october-agenda-talks</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
